applicanttree.com 2009-05-11

# Privacy Policy

|   
At Applicant Tree, we recognize that privacy is important. This Policy applies to all the products, Services and Web sites offered by Applicant Tree or its subsidiaries or affiliated companies (collectively, Applicant Tree's "Services"). In addition, where more detailed information is needed to explain our privacy practices, we post separate Privacy notices to describe how particular Services process personal information.  
Information We Collect and How We Use It  

In order to provide quality, comprehensive service to job seekers, we may collect the following types of information:   
Information You Provide  

When you sign up for an Applicant Tree account or other Applicant Tree service or promotion that requires registration, we ask you for personal information such as your name, e-mail address and an account password. For certain Services, such as our payment programs, we also request credit card or other payment account information that we maintain in encrypted form on secure servers. We may combine the information you submit under your account with information from other Applicant Tree Services or third parties in order to provide you with a better experience and to improve the quality of our Services. For certain Services, we may give you the opportunity to opt out of combining such information.   
Applicant Tree Cookies  

When you visit Applicant Tree, we send one or more cookies – small files containing a string of characters – to your computer in order to uniquely identify your browser. We use cookies to improve the quality of our service by storing user preferences and tracking user trends, such as how people search. Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies, but you can reset your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, some Applicant Tree features and Services may not function properly if your cookies are disabled.   
Referrals  

Users have the option to provide names and e-mail addresses of friends for the purpose of referring them to the Applicant Tree site or a job opportunity. When you refer friends, the name and e-mail address provided may be retained in our database. We will send them a one-time e-mail inviting them to visit the site or view the job opportunity you wish them to see.   
Log Information  

When you use Applicant Tree Services, our servers automatically record information that your browser sends whenever you visit a Web site. These server logs may include information such as your Web request, Internet Protocol address, browser type, browser language, the date and time of your request and one or more cookies that may uniquely identify your browser.   
User Communications  

When you send e-mail or other communication to Applicant Tree, we may retain those communications in order to process your inquiries, respond to your requests and improve our Services.   
Affiliated Sites  

We offer some of our Services in connection with other Web sites. Personal information that you provide to those sites may be sent to Applicant Tree in order to deliver the service. We process such information in accordance with this Policy. The affiliated sites may have different privacy practices and we encourage you to read their privacy policies.   
Links  

Applicant Tree may present links in a format that enables us to keep track of whether these links have been followed. We use this information to improve the quality of our technologies and Services and on some occasions for affiliate program tracking and advertising purposes.   
Other Sites  

This Privacy Policy applies to Web sites and Services that are owned and operated by Applicant Tree. We do not exercise control over the sites displayed as content or links from within our various Services. These other sites may place their own cookies or other files on your computer, collect data or solicit personal information from you. 

Applicant Tree only processes personal information for the purposes described in the applicable Privacy Policy and/or privacy notice for specific Services. In addition to the above, such purposes include: 

  * Providing our products and Services to users, including the display of customized content and advertising; 
  * Auditing, research and analysis in order to maintain, protect and improve our Services; 
  * Ensuring the technical functioning of our network; and 
  * Developing new Services.

Applicant Tree processes personal information on our servers in the United States of America and in other countries. In some cases, we process personal information on a server outside your own country. We may process personal information to provide our own Services. In some cases, we may process personal information on behalf of and according to the instructions of a third party, such as our advertising partners.   
Choices For Personal Information  

When you sign up for a particular Service that requires registration, we ask you to provide personal information. If we use this information in a manner different from the purpose for which it was collected, then we will ask for your consent prior to such use. 

If we propose to use personal information for any purposes other than those described in this Policy and/or in the specific service notices, we will offer you an effective way to opt out of the use of personal information for those other purposes. We will not collect or use sensitive information for purposes other than those described in this Policy and/or in the specific service notices, unless we have obtained your prior consent. 

You can decline to submit personal information to any of our Services, in which case Applicant Tree may not be able to provide those Services to you.   
  
Information Sharing  

Applicant Tree only shares personal information with other companies or individuals outside of Applicant Tree in the following limited circumstances: 

  * When we have your consent. We require opt-in consent for the sharing of any sensitive personal information.
  * Providing such information to our subsidiaries, affiliated companies or other trusted businesses or persons is necessary for the purpose of processing personal information on our behalf. We require that these parties agree to process such information based on our instructions and in compliance with this Policy and any other appropriate confidentiality and security measures.
  * When we have a good-faith belief that access, use, preservation or disclosure of such information is reasonably necessary to (a) satisfy any applicable law, regulation, legal process or enforceable governmental request; (b) enforce applicable Terms of Service, including investigation of potential violations thereof; (c) detect, prevent or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues; or (d) protect against imminent harm to the rights, property or safety of Applicant Tree, its users or the public as required or permitted by law.

If Applicant Tree becomes involved in a merger, acquisition or any form of sale of some or all of its assets, we will provide notice before personal information is transferred and becomes subject to a different privacy policy. 

We may share with third parties certain pieces of aggregated, non-personal information, such as the number of users who registered or received offers for a particular term, for example, or how many users clicked on a particular advertisement. Such information does not identify you individually. 

Please contact us at the address below for any additional questions about the management or use of personal data.   
  
Information Security  

We take appropriate security measures to protect against unauthorized access to or unauthorized alteration, disclosure or destruction of data. These include internal reviews of our data collection, storage and processing practices and security measures, as well as physical security measures to guard against unauthorized access to systems where we store personal data. 

We restrict access to personal information to Applicant Tree employees, contractors and agents who need to know that information in order to operate, develop or improve our Services. These individuals are bound by confidentiality obligations and may be subject to discipline, including termination and criminal prosecution, if they fail to meet these obligations.   
  
Data Integrity  

Applicant Tree processes personal information only for the purposes for which it was collected and in accordance with this Policy or any applicable Service-specific privacy notice. We review our data collection, storage and processing practices to ensure that we only collect, store and process the personal information needed to provide or improve our Services. We take reasonable steps to ensure that the personal information we process is accurate, complete and current, but we depend on our users to update or correct their personal information whenever necessary.   
Accessing And Updating Personal Information  

When you use Applicant Tree Services, we make good-faith efforts to provide you with access to your personal information and either to correct this data if it is inaccurate or to delete such data at your request if it is not otherwise required to be retained by law or for legitimate business purposes. We ask individual users to identify themselves and the information requested to be accessed, corrected or removed before processing such requests, and we may decline to process requests that are unreasonably repetitive or systematic, require disproportionate technical effort, jeopardize the privacy of others or would be extremely impractical (for instance, requests concerning information residing on backup tapes), or for which access is not otherwise required. In any case where we provide information access and correction, we perform this service free of charge, except if doing so would require a disproportionate effort. Some of our Services have different procedures to access, correct or delete users' personal information.   
Activating, Pausing, And Deactivating An Account  

To activate an account, you are agreeing to submit your information to Applicant Tree's Web site and database. In the event that you no longer wish to be part of Applicant Tree, you may either pause or deactivate your account. 

Pausing one's account is to temporarily stop it. You will still be a registered user of the Web site, however companies will not be able to see or access your resume. We will retain the information gathered about you within the system indefinitely. If you wish to reactivate your account, you are able to by simply signing back in and changing your status.   
  
Enforcement  

Applicant Tree regularly reviews its compliance with this Policy. Please feel free to direct any questions or concerns regarding this Policy or Applicant Tree's treatment of personal information by contacting us through this Web site or by writing to us at: 

Applicant Tree   
7320 East Fletcher Ave  
Tampa, FL 33637

Or, if You prefer, please call or e-mail Applicant Tree at:  
Telephone: 813-864-6271  
E-mail: [info@applicanttree.com](mailto:info@applicanttree.com)

When we receive formal written complaints at this address, it is Applicant Tree's policy to contact the complaining user regarding his or her concerns. We will cooperate with the appropriate regulatory authorities, including local data protection authorities, to resolve any complaints regarding the transfer of personal data that cannot be resolved between Applicant Tree and an individual.   
  
Changes To This Policy  

Please note that this Privacy Policy may change from time to time. We will not reduce your rights under this Policy without your explicit consent, and we expect most such changes will be minor. Regardless, we will post any Policy changes on this page and, if the changes are significant, we will provide a more prominent notice (including, for certain Services, e-mail notification of Policy changes). Each version of this Policy will be identified at the top of the page by its effective date, and we will also keep prior versions of this Privacy Policy in an archive for your review. 

If you have any additional questions or concerns about this Policy, please feel free to contact us any time through this Web site or using  
the contact information we have provided. 

Updated 3/1/2008
